Up to this point, we've only been working with one table at a time.
حتى هذه المرحلة، لم نتعامل سوى مع جدول واحد في كل مرة فقط.
But the real power of SQL comes from working with data across multiple tables at once.
لكن تأتي القوة الحقيقية لـ SQL من التعامل مع البيانات عبر جداول متعددة في وقت واحد.
The term relational database refers to
يُشير مصطلح قاعدة البيانات الارتباطية إلى
the fact that tables within it relate to one another.
الحقيقة التي تفيد بأن الجداول الموجودة بداخلها ترتبط ببعضها البعض.
They contain common identifiers that allow
إنها تحتوي على معرّفات شائعة تسمح
information from multiple tables to be easily combined.
بجمع المعلومات المستخلصة من جداول متعددة بسهولة.
Keeping all of a company's data, from purchasing transactions,
إن الاحتفاظ بجميع بيانات الشركة، بداية من معاملات الشراء،
to employee job satisfaction,
ومرورًا بالرضا الوظيفي للموظفين،
to inventory in a single Excel dataset doesn't make a ton of sense.
ووصولاً إلى المخزون في مجموعة بيانات واحدة في Excel لا يبدو ذا مغزى.
The table would hold a ton of information and it'd be hard
سيحتفظ الجدول بالكثير من المعلومات وسيكون من الصعب
to determine a row call and structure for so many different types of data.
تحديد استدعاء صف أو بنية لعدد كبير من أنواع البيانات المختلفة.
Databases give us the flexibility to keep things organized neatly in their own tables,
تعطينا قواعد البيانات المرونة للحفاظ على العناصر منظّمة بدقة في جداولها الخاصة،
so that they're easy to find and work with while also allowing us to
بحيث يسهّل العثور عليها والتعامل معها بالإضافة إلى أنها تسمح لنا أيضًا
combine tables as needed to solve problems that require several types of data.
بجمع الجداول حسب الحاجة لحل المشكلات التي تحتاج إلى أنواع عديدة من البيانات.
In this lesson, we're going to take a look at
في هذا الدرس، سنلقي نظرة على
how to leverage SQL to link tables together.
كيفية الاستفادة من SQL لربط الجداول معًا.
You're about to see why SQL is one of the most popular environments for
أنت على وشك معرفة السبب الذي يجعل SQL واحدة من البيئات الأكثر شيوعًا
working with data as we learn how to write what are known as Joints.
للتعامل مع البيانات أثناء معرفتنا كيفية كتابة ما الذي يُعرف باسم الوصلات.